Hey team.
>> Oh gee.
>> Are we late
>> guys?
>> Good to be here.
>> Go America.
>> Go America. Team America.com.
>> Yes indeed. So America right brothers.
First man on the moon. The internet.
>> The two of us. Wright brothers.
>> I like that. Indeed. We've we've
essentially led every major
technological revolution which has been
to the enormous benefit of America,
ordinary Americans. We're I guess we're
now calling this super intelligence,
which I think is actually good branding.
And so let's let's talk about how
America wins this and we make that
winning good for ordinary Americans.
Well,
um excuse me, Diet Coke. Sorry.
So first of all, artificial super
intelligence, super intelligence
is a a complete reinvention of the
computing stack. Uh everything from the
way the processors, the chips are are
designed and the way they operate to the
way software is uh now trained and and
developed to the way that the
applications are able to perform what
they're able to do and how they how they
perform. Every single layer of the
computing stack has been reinvented. Um
this way of doing computing unlike
previous ways of retrieving information,
this is a generative approach to to
computing and therefore in order for us
to succeed the first thing we need is
energy because we need the energies to
to run the compute. the compute run the
algorithms. the algorithms um then feed
the applications. And so at the at the
foundational layer is energy and uh from
that energy we build the land power and
shel and that host the infrastructure so
on so forth. And so the way we win um of
course we are world class in chip
design. We're world class in algorithm
development. Um and uh uh and so one of
the things that we need to do is just be
vigilant about enabling power delivery
and power generation to happen. And
President Trump has been has been
visionary in being pro- energy. Without
the pro-energy vision of President
Trump, it would have been impossible for
us to build the data centers on top of
it. Um now, of course, uh these data
centers are coming online so quickly. Uh
we're we're uh uh coming into a lot of
neighborhoods and a lot of communities.
We have to do a better job um in
partnering with the communities and and
to make and bring them along and make
them part of the prosperity and the
success of this industrial revolution.
Um but you know that's how we win. You
know we got to build the world's best
chips. We got to build it. We have to
have lots and lots of energy. Uh create
incredible algorithms. And then lastly,
make sure that America is enthusiastic
about the technology so that we diffuse
it into all of these various industries
from manufacturing to healthcare, you
know, space space exploration, so on so
forth.
>> Awesome. Elon, how do we win? How do we
keep winning?
Well,
we need um a lot of power, a lot of
energy uh generation. So, uh
scaling energy, I think, is is one of
the biggest things. You've got to scale
energy, you've got to scale chip
production. Um and I I think we're we're
winning on software on on anything
intellectual or digital. Um but uh long
in the long run we need to be able to
generate enough power uh to compete with
uh I think essentially China is the
biggest competitor and and chi China has
um about three times the electricity
production of the United States. Um and
I think we'll figure out how to make
ships. So
so the the really the central challenge
I think is long long term is going to be
how do you generate enough power And how
do you ensure that uh we have enough uh
logic and memory fabrication capacity in
the United States or in a safe region?
>> Well, you are
>> we need we need the right brothers on a
job.
>> Yes. Well, it turns out the right
brothers are on the job. Elon, if you
bring on 10 gigawatts, which SpaceX has
has discussed publicly, that'll be about
25% of all the power added in America.
And I know you have literal rocket
engineers working on bringing on the
power.
>> Yeah.
>> Helping make the turbines. So can you
can you talk about that?
>> Yeah, it's I mean just to to frame this
um the average power consumption in the
United States is about 500 gawatt. So
every 5 gawatt of incremental
steadystate production is a 1% increase
in in the power used um and and I think
actually will materialize to be
approximately 1% increase in GDP um
because the the intelligence for what
keeps increasing. So if you just you
know plot on a curve um how is how is
the useful intelligence per what
increasing um how is the both at the
hardware level at Jensen's uh GPUs keep
getting better in terms of their the you
know the the compute per watt um and the
uh algorithms also get better in using
and getting more intelligence per watt
so u so I think that's a maybe an
interesting note I I I would bet anyone
that 1% increase in power usage
corresponds to roughly 1% increase in
GDP and and so 10 10 gigawatts will be a
2% increase in in GDP um with with the
Reuben I think um so
>> well let's do let's do the simple math
so each gigawatt um can probably
generate about call it 4050 billion
dollars of economic output each year
>> uh yeah I mean 1 1% would be yeah I mean
>> 1% of the United States would be
>> 300 300 billion.
>> Yeah. 300 billion. And so 506
>> what 1% of the of the 1% increase. So 5
gawatt would be Yeah. Well 5 gawatt
would be 300 billion. Yeah. Exactly. 60
60 billion a g. Yeah. That's right.
>> The math maths.
>> Yeah.
>> That's what we're good at.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> So so that's that's quite
>> not good at too many other things but
math.
>> Um yeah. I mean, it's it's going to
increase quite dramatically
year-over-year.
So,
yeah. I mean,
and and from a SpaceX standpoint, we're
looking at long-term, how do we access a
lot more energy than could be accessed
on the ground and and that's with space.
So, uh orbital compute is going to be a
very big deal. Um in fact, and and
Google agrees. They they just actually
sent up uh or are either about to or
soon soon about to send up some TPUs. I
think there's that there was a um an
H100 that was put into orbit like last
year, I think.
>> Mhm.
>> Um so it it does work in in space and um
and and SpaceX is aiming together with
Tesla to do 200 gawatts of solar
production per year. And if brought to
space that you get the name plate or
better on on the solar power whereas if
it's on the ground you're going to get
somewhere between a fifth and an eighth
of the uh solar power generation and you
need enormous batteries. So whereas it's
uh essentially always sunny in space. So
uh and right now is a great time to do
it because the economic returns of these
computing systems are so good. Yeah.
that the the launch cost although is
still quite high um in terms of the
overall economic benefit is quite quite
affordable.
>> Absolutely.
>> This is the perfect time to do it.
>> Putting Nvidia computing in space is the
best way to get there.
>> Yeah. Climbing the card of scale with
American power and American chips on
American rockets. I love it.
>> Yeah. So Jensen, you said something that
I thought was important about how
when we bring the energy to all these
small towns, we're reindustrializing
America. We're revitalizing small towns.
We're modernizing the grid. These are
things that essentially every American
politician has wanted for the last 35
years. What would you say? What what
what are some specifics you can give
about how data centers are good for
ordinary Americans in the communities
and how they're getting better for those
communities?
>> Yeah, we used to call them data centers.
We call them data centers because that's
where we hold data.
>> But the things that we're building now,
these are really SI factories, super
intelligence factories. And the reason
why it's a factory is because you're
producing something of economic value.
You're just not storing it. And so so uh
these SI factories um are real
factories. Uh it's like a you know big
giant power generator and real
factories. It's got a lot of computing
in there, networking in there, power
generation, cooling systems. It's
complicated things. And so we're
building out you know just as the
internet today allows you to find
anything anywhere in the future with
these AI, excuse me, SI infrastructure,
SI factories, you'll be able to know
anything and do anything from anywhere.
And so uh now we're building this
infrastructure out and you know call it
uh across all of the United States uh
somewhere between 10 uh 20 gawatts a
year. Let's just just estimate that
creates just you know probably about a
million jobs in in building out these
data centers. Don't forget you've got to
build the power generation plants. You
got to build the data centers. You've
got construction. You've got you know
power cooling. You've got you know pipe
fitters. And so this is the first time
in probably as you mentioned 35 I was
going to say 50 years first time in 50
years we are re-industrializing the
United States creating a whole bunch of
bluecollar jobs and um I and I think we
want we want an econ we want an economy
that has a shape that includes white
collar jobs and blue collar jobs not
just white collar jobs and so so I think
that this is our great chance of
reshaping our economy and bringing that
type
builders and craft backed into the
United States.
>> Absolutely. And it I mean it feels like
what uh what Colossus
and Macro hard and macro harder have
done have been amazing for the
communities around them, the jobs
they've created. How do you how do you
think about that?
>> Uh yeah, the I mean the economic impact
is positive economic impact has been
tremendous. Um I mean we we there's
actually a job shortage in in the region
and whereas there used to be uh quite a
bit of unemployment and now it's uh
there's this there's a overmployment if
you will there's there's more jobs than
than there are people um and the the tax
benefits uh for the community have been
tremendous. I think the I think we might
have doubled their their tax budget or
something um quite quite tremendous.
Then we we do like small things that are
helpful like provide you know low price
halfp price stallink uh access. Um we're
building a water recycling plant that's
a $250 million water recycling plant. Um
I think you you do need to do things for
the community. Um and if you do so they
will reciprocate.
>> Awesome. Now, one of the the things that
people people forget is that for the
first time in in probably forever that
we have the market forces to support the
investment of sustainable energy. You
give me an example of a fusion fision,
you know, small nuclear reactor, large
reactor, almost every form of
sustainable energy is being funded
today. And so we have the opportunity to
fund the future of energy without
without the government subsidizing,
without Right. I mean we this is you
give me an example of a great energy
battery storage idea. It's going to get
funded.
>> Awesome. By by the way on behalf of all
Americans I want to thank both of you. I
think combined you have created more
than5 trillion dollars of wealth for
ordinary Americans in their 401ks.
Tens of thousands maybe hundreds of
thousands of jobs directly many tens of
billions of wages. So thank you. Um,
>> I think Jensen has done 5 trillion by
himself, actually.
>> I'm sorry.
>> I think Jensen's done five trillion by
himself.
>> I think I think I think around three and
a half or something.
>> Yeah.
>> I was trying I was trying to be
conservative. Yes.
>> So, you guys both had a great Monday. I
was watching the uh Starship launch,
first orbital Starship launch while I
was reading about the open agent safety
framework from Nvidia. Uh which was an
exciting morning. Uh so may maybe you
could each talk about each of those
because we need Starship to get those
200 gawatts of American solder with
American chips, American super
intelligence into orbit.
>> I'll talk about his and he talks on
mine.
>> So no, I'm just kidding. So, so um uh
let's see. As you know, we want to
advance AI. Advance SI. We I'm going to
get good at this. We're going to advance
SI in a in a responsible uh and
optimistic way. And we we know that the
future uh we strongly believe that the
future that SI is going to enable is a
future that we want to be part of. And
so, we're optimistic about that. And
that's the reason why we're driving so
hard. On the other hand, we have to make
sure that we develop this technology
safely and securely. Um there are
several different parts of it. While
you're training the model, um that's
that's generally a fairly safe
environment. But while you're evaluating
the model, while you're testing the
model, you have to make sure that the
agent agentic system, the model itself
is highly contained. That containment
system has to be really secure. And the
second thing is that while you're while
you're testing it, you want to monitor
that that just because just even though
even though you have it contained, you
should never trust that it's contained.
And so you want to monitor it in real
time. And you want to ideally monitor it
with another another chip so that it is
outside, you know, if you will call out
of band outside the environment, outside
the sandbox of the agent itself. And so
you want to contain and you want to
monitor. Um once you're done uh
evaluating in this way, when you deploy,
you want to use a very similar system.
You know, this is no different than than
um uh just about any digital any human
employee that you hire. Uh you give them
a containment of rights and tools and
access. Uh and then you monitor on on a
regular basis on a continuous basis. And
so in the case of agents, we just have
to make sure containment and monitoring
has to be done in the most secure of
ways. And we in introduced two
technologies. One's called open shell.
Uh it's a a containment system. Uh it's
basically kind of like a browser for
websites. It's now essentially a browser
of agents. Um and that browser keeps uh
the agent isolated from the rest of the
computer and the rights that you give it
are only the rights it should have. And
then the the the monitoring system uh is
a a new chip called Bluefield and it it
just keeps an eye on everything that the
agent is doing at all times. And if it
does anything that's, you know, out of
bounds and against the policy that has
been given, uh, then it, you know,
escalates, uh, as far as you need it to
escalate.
>> And I thought it was a great analogy in
in the technical blog where you said in
the early days of internet, everybody
was worried about your credit card could
get stolen. We made the internet safe
and that's why we have Amazon, we have
Netflix, we have Google, we have X, we
have so many so many great things
because we made the internet safe. Now
we're do now now we're doing the same
with AI
>> and safety is not you know inconsistent
with advancing the technology. Safety
and advancing a technology is one in the
same thing. It's no different than than
um uh when you have autopilot not only
is it advanced technology is also safer
technology. And so you want you advance
the technology in that way. Um the two
are not in conflict. Um the idea that if
you advance capability it somehow
compromises safety. if you have man
safety somehow you fall behind that
that's just that you know those are
false choices
>> yeah safety lets us accelerate but Elon
if the starship's going to be a big part
of those 200 gawatts what can you tell
us about Monday's flight what you
learned how you feeling about the
program
>> yeah I think the starship is going great
uh we we uh we took Starship to orbit
for the first time and we deployed uh
Starlink B3 satellites which are
enormous satellites I mean these are
satellites with the wingspan of a 737
seven. So, u really really enormous. Uh
in fact, it's it's the largest payload
delivered to orbit since Skylab.
So, uh now we expect Starship to uh
ultimately next year I think probably
reach um a weekly or twice weekly
cadence.
>> We've got not Tom Brown here. I know him
by his exhandle. Welcome.
>> Good to see you guys again.
>> Um
Yes, it was.
>> Uh my my car took a wrong turn, so you
guys got here faster than me.
Impressive.
>> Glad you made it.
>> So, but Elon, please please continue.
We're talking about how Starship is
going to let us get to 200 gigs of
American solar with American chips, with
American super intelligence.
>> Yeah. So, I mean, Starship is going to
do a lot of things. It's I mean, it's
intended uh to uh carry enough payload
to the moon and Mars to build a
self-growing city on the moon or Mars.
So um I mean I think as a rough order of
magnitude you need about a million tons
to deliver to the surface of the moon to
uh create a self-growing city or
similarly sim similar number for Mars.
Um and and and then in addition it will
launch um at least a few hundred gawatts
a year of uh AI compute. Um 200 gawatts
a year would be a 40% increase annually
in the United States total energy uh
consumption. So that's quite a quite a
big number. Um, and it might end up
being a terowatt one day. Um, so this is
this is serious tonnage.
>> Awesome. And and Tom, uh, Enthropic, uh,
your your company, you're a co-founder
of Enthropic. You announced Opus 5.5 in
the last several days. And I thought
maybe we'd go to the exponential that we
are on. And I think it's helpful to
ground what can Opus 5.5 and maybe it's
for everybody. What can Opus 5.5 do to
make the lives of ordinary Americans
better today and where are we going to
be in a year?
>> Yeah. So, um, Opus 55 is uh a model that
I think just continues the normal
progress that we've had of getting kind
of more IQ points for each of these
super intelligences uh with each model
release. Um, and so the main things that
people will see if they use it now is
that it can do a task that takes a
longer time than they'd be able to
delegate to to a previous model. Um, and
so I think the things that people should
see is just like as a normal American,
if you want a task, if you want to
actually delegate a task to it, it will
be able to do that better is one thing.
And then two is a thing that I think
people notice less, which is just that
there's going to be a huge amount of
software being written by these models.
And so all of the products that people
use are going to be getting higher
quality, cheaper over time. And it'll
have this effect of just like
all of the all of the tools that we use
now were written by like people doing
engineering work. And now it's going to
be written by both people and super
intelligence is doing much much more
engineering work than was possible
before.
>> Absolutely. But I think it's doing so
much more than this. There's already
multiple stories of AI, I'm sorry, super
intelligence, super intelligence finding
a life-saving drug that can be used for
a disease that it wasn't understood that
it could safely treat. So, it's saving
lives. I think it's having profound
impacts on education, but may maybe each
of you could talk for ordinary
Americans. What's super intelligence
doing today? And what's it going to be
able to do in a year? I'm an ordinary
American
and uh I use I use um uh Claude to uh
help me do research and and um instead
of giving me just answers and most of my
research that maybe there's comparative
research that I'm doing and there's two
or three different approaches to
something and I wanted to answer a list
of different questions and uh compare
and contrast uh rates of rates of growth
or rates of change or whatever it is.
And so I describe literally, you know,
every single question I have and nothing
gives me more joy than and then and I
ask it to create a nice report and and
plot it out and sometimes it's a pie
chart, sometimes a bar graph and I just
hit enter and nothing gives me more joy
than just watch it go and it comes back
and it creates a beautiful, you know,
beautiful report and and then instead of
instead of researching all these
different topics for four, six, eight
hours, which back in the old days I
would on a weekend, you know, learn
something new, It goes off and creates
me this really really beautiful final
report in about three minutes and you
know it's all condensed and now you're
getting smarter faster.
>> Love it.
>> What about for you? How is how do you
how are you seeing super intelligence
helping ordinary Americans and what do
you think it'll do in a year or two?
Maybe a year or two. Take a year or two
from now.
>> Yeah. Well, I I think it's it's helping
people organize their lives and uh do
better at their jobs. So, I think it
really will become um essential if it
isn't already for people to use AI uh
for in their professional lives
certainly and and in their private
lives. And so, AI is just an incredibly
helpful, useful thing. Um, you know,
I've heard many anecdotes of AI helping
people uh with medical issues. Um, and
in in many cases where the the doctor
was wrong and the they they submitted
their X-rays or MRI to to AI and and AI
got it right and and but but for AI,
they would have died. And I've heard
many such cases.
>> Awesome. And hopefully Opus 56 tells
Tom, "Don't take that left, take the
right."
>> Hopefully,
>> I think it's important these these super
intelligences, they are imbued with the
values of their creators and we do have
there there are American values that we
all share. The first amendment, free
speech, commitment to truth.
Can you can you talk about what each of
you are doing to imbue help make sure
that these these super intelligences are
imbued with with the right values?
>> Are we allowed to say anything
controversial?
>> Say something controversial.
>> Okay. So so um I
the the SIS are are tools and and the
challenge with an SI with values uh
meaning it has judgment. um depending on
how you use that SI, it may decide uh um
how it deci it may judge you and it's
effectiveness would be affected by that
judgment. And so it's a little bit like
a steak knife where if you if you uh
were served medium well, it cuts
perfectly, but if you were served rare
steak and it looks awfully like live
meat, somehow it doesn't cut. And so I I
think there's a there's a you know
there's a there's a question in my mind
yet about how much judgment you really
want these tools to have. And and so
that that the intentions of the user um
you know obviously I use I use the knife
as an example but you can think of a
whole bunch of other examples. Uh the
intentions are a little bit different.
you know whether you're a defender or an
attacker for example in cyber security
the defender's actions could resemble an
attacker and you want the defender you
want this SI to um activate on behalf of
the defender even though it appears to
be an you know an aggressive action.
>> Great. I think we're running up on time
but maybe if you guys could share you
spent a lot of time at the White House.
Is there anything that that you can
share share with the world about what
came out of what was evidently a a uh a
long and productive lunch?
>> We did good.
>> Yeah.
>> We we signed a joint declaration
uh regarding SI safety. Um and uh I
think I think that'll be published by
the White House soon if it hasn't been
already. Uh but uh we we agreed to to a
number of things that uh include joint
monitoring um board special committees
and u just generally uh grading each
other's homework which is a lot better
than if people just grade their own
homework uh for obvious reasons
>> and and includes every it includes
everything from um rigorous internal
controls um wellestablished methods well
established processes um very clearly
documented intentions of the products So
you're building internal controls to
make sure that you're delivering on
those intentions. Um internal audit um
that that escalates uh external audits
um from from a third party and uh um and
then industries sharing best practices.
I I thought that the the the declaration
has has a lot of teeth. Um, I thought it
was really well written and um, uh, I
think this is a a practice that that
quite frankly as a standards for our
industry going forward. Um, every every
single company ought to out of embrace
and so pus pis pulled it all together.
Uh, he he um watched over the meeting
and uh, uh, was able to bring everybody
out and um, you know, I thought it was
it was really wellrun.
>> Awesome. Well, on behalf of all
Americans, thank thank all of you for
doing everything you can to make the
future as awesome and optimistic for
American Americans as you can. And you
are. So, thank you.